Baptist Society of Pompey, New York Records
Baptist Society of Pompey, New York Records
1799-1943
Baptist Society of Pompey, New York
1 linear ft.
Records of the church in Pompey, located in central New York. Collection includes financial, administrative, membership, legal, and printed material as well as three volumes of meeting minutes.
2538174
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Baptist Society of Pompey Records includes financial, administrative, membership, and legal Church records; related Printed material including a copy of the Church manual and some clippings; and three volumes of Church and Covenant meeting minute books.
Arrangement of the Collection
Church records are arranged alphabetically by type. Printed material and meeting minute books are arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Church and clergy; Baptist Society of Pompey, New York.; Baptists -- New York (State) -- Pompey.; Church records and registers -- New York (State) -- Pompey.; New York (State) -- Social life and customs.; Articles.; Church registers.; Clippings (information artifacts); Financial records.; Microfilms.; Minutes (administrative records)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Church records
  - Accounts payable, 1816-1929 (Box 1)
  - Annual reports and letters, 1923-1942; undated (Box 1)
  - Attendance record, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Bank statements, 1921; 1923,; 1927 (Box 1)
  - Blank forms, undated (Box 1)
  - Certificates of membership and letter of dismissal, 1801-1936 (Box 1)
  - Church articles of practice and Church Covenant, undated (Box 1)
  - Confession of sin
    - Pearce vs. Cooley, 1816-1823 (Box 1)
    - Coats vs. Warren, 1818 (Box 1)
  - Confession of faith, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, incoming, 1805-1943 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, 1805-1929 (Box 1)
  - Declaration of Withdrawal, 1896 (Box 1)
  - Deed, 1799 (Box 1)
  - Insurance, 1927-1928 (Box 1)
  - Lane, Elder Benjamin, 1819; 1922 (Box 1)
  - Legal Matters, 1883-1926 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1805-1938; undated; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Missionary report, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Opinion on communion, 1822 (Box 1)
  - Receipts, 1817-1934 (Box 1)
  - Reports from neighboring churches, 1833; 1838,; undated (Box 1)
  - Succession of ministers, 1805-1825 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer’s report, 1846-1933 (Box 1)
  - Poems, undated (Box 1)
- Printed material
  - Baptist Church Manual, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Church Insurance Association, 1892 (Box 1)
  - "Country church once more" by W.A. Grange, undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1915; undated; history of the church building (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1925; undated (Box 1)
- Church and Covenant meeting minute books
  - 1805-1835, Pompey/Delphi Male members, female members, organizational records, Articles of Faith, Articles of Practice, Church Covenant, minutes (Volume 1)
  - 1835-1875, 1914, 1934, 1935, Male members, female members, Articles of Faith and Practice of the Baptist Church, Delphi, Covenant, Accords of the Baptist Church, Delphi, miscellaneous. Also, lists of members from 1914, correspondence from 1934, Baptist church Manual, 1935. (Volume 2)
  - 1875-1924, 1916, Record and property of the First Baptist Church of the Town of Pompey at Delphi, 1875. Articles of Faith and Practice, Covenant, membership, minutes of Covenant meetings, printed article on the Delphi Church building erected in 1916. (Volume 3)
- Microfilm
  - Microfilm 22 - First Baptist Society, Town of Pompey, Onondaga County, NY (Box 1)